Preliminary Inventory of the Zhongguo Gong Chan Dang Issuances
Hoover Institution Archives
Zhongguo gong chan dang issuances
1919-2006
2002C15
Hoover Institution Archives
33 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (14.8 linear feet)
Internal documents, books, pamphlets, serial issues, broadsides, and flyers relating to political, military, social, and economic conditions in China at the national, provincial, and local levels.
Zhongguo gong chan dang.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2002 with an increment in 2012.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
Chinese Communist Party.
Scope and Content of Collection
Internal documents, books, pamphlets, serial issues, broadsides, and flyers relating to political, military, social, and economic conditions in China at the national, provincial, and local levels.
An increment received in 2012 consists of more than two hundred pieces of historical material relating to the Chinese Cultural Revolution. It contains nearly two hundred issues of the Red Guard "little newspapers" published between 1967 and 1971 and other communist pamphlets, internal party documents, booklets, serial issues, and published speeches of communist leaders during this period.
China--Economic conditions 1949-; China--History--Cultural Revolution, 1966-1976.; China--Military policy.; China--Politics and government--1949-; China--Social conditions--1949-; Communism--China.
- Internal Party Reports, 1973-1991 (Box 1-2)
  - Mao Zedong's conversation with Kissinger, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Hua Guofeng speech, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Instructions on fighting against counter-revolutionary sabotage, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Mao Zedong conversation with Ho Chi Minh in Hangzhou, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Deepening the struggle against Hu and Chen counter-revolutionary group, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - "Historical Issues of the Party," draft, 1981-1987 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - 11th central committee 6th meeting materials, 1981, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 1: 7-8)
  - An Ping incident, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Conference against capitalism classes, report, 1967 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Hua Zhangxi file, 1950-1970 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Zhou Tielin file, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - "5/16" incident, 1971 (Box-folder 2: 5-6)
  - Report of individuals, 1958-1970 (Box-folder 2: 7-8)
  - Miscellaneous report, 1943-1971 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Party Cadre Member Files, 1956-1987 (Box 3)
  - Liu Changgen, "materials to be destroyed,", 1982 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Ji Xiying, 1956-1973 (Box-folder 3: 2-3)
  - Wu Shaocheng, 1972 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Wang Shizhi, 1972 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Fan Chuide, 1970 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Individuals' files, 1967-1987 (Box-folder 3: 7-8)
  - Cadre member files, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 3: 9-10)
- First Design Institution of Light Industry Reports, 1950-1987 (Box 4-6)
  - Index of files of cadre members, 1950-1970 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - First Design Institution of Light Industry files, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 4: 2-3)
  - Xiao Zi Bao, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - File to be destroyed, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 5-6)
  - Materials regarding the case of "Ge,", undated (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Materials of the incident where the Design Institution was searched without warrant, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Punishment decisions on individuals involved in illegal search, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Chu Lu file, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Ma Qian file, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Illegal search public report, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Speech regarding the incident of "5/16,", 1972 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Materials regarding the incident of "5/16,", 1972 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Dong Feng communication material, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Materials written by Deng Liangyi, 1969 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Issues about Zhong Nan Hai, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Speech of investigated targets, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - External materials, 1984 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - File of individuals with common issues, 1987 (Box-folder 6: 7)
- "5/16 Movement" Investigation Reports, 1967-1971 (Box 7-8)
  - Comprehensive confession material, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
  - "Design Red Flag," introduction, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Zhao Xiuying diary, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Liu Jiying confession, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Peng Zhengao confession, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Zhong Nan Hai incident, speeches, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Zhang Shichun, Liu Junliang confession, 1971 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Anonymous diary, 1971 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - "5/16 Movement," general report, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 7: 10-11)
  - Police record of "5/16" incident, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Guo Shuchun revelation material, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 2-3)
  - Investigation group meeting minutes, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Li Deheng profile, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 5-6)
  - Lin Jiying profile, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 7)
- Class Struggle in the Chinese Cultural Revolution File, 1949-1995 (Box 9-11)
  - Critics on Liang Sumin's idealism, 1995 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Shandong Supreme Court materials, 1956 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Yi Peng Dehuai Wei Shou De Fan Dang Ji Tuan De Jue Yi, 1959 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - "A Revolutionary Granaries,", 1964 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Critics on Liu Shaoqi's economic revisionism, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Agricultural Department correspondence, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Wan Shan naval battle, 1975 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - Outline of Xi'an incident, 1982 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - Temporary regulations on religious activities, 1982 (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Xin Jiang Poverty Alleviation Office instructions, 1994 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Beijing Air Force materials, 1984 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Beijing, Xi Yu area, Bureau of Justice work summary, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - Zui Cao Zhi Shi (The Utmost Instructions), undated (Box-folder 9: 13)
  - Shou Du Feng Lei, newspaper, undated (Box-folder 9: 14)
  - Li Qi correspondence, undated (Box-folder 9: 15)
  - New China, foreign cultural exchange memorabilia, 1949-1966 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Experience exchange in education, 1953 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Arrest policies for counter-revolutionaries and other criminals, 1953 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Shan Xi rectification movement, 1957 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Rightists' quotations on industrial and transportation systems, 1957 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Xu Futang, self review, 1957 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - Important study materials, 1960 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Unidentified work diary, 1961 (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - Preliminary screening and positive screening of the anti-rightist movement, 1962 (Box-folder 10: 9)
  - Yang Zhi material, 1964 (Box-folder 10: 10)
  - Critics on Wang Ming's revisionism, 1966 (Box-folder 10: 11)
  - Survey materials of Lei Jiande, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 10: 12)
  - "Marxism-Leninism and the Ideology of Party Members,", undated (Box-folder 10: 13)
  - "Socialist Revolution in Ideology and Politics,", undated (Box-folder 10: 14)
  - "The Struggle Is Getting Deeper," press release draft, undated (Box-folder 10: 15)
  - Li Yaxing's anti-party, anti-socialism remarks, undated (Box-folder 10: 16)
  - "What is Liberalism?," Yang Dongling, undated (Box-folder 10: 17)
  - "The Class Character of Humans,", undated (Box-folder 10: 18)
  - Chinese history study, 1955 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Zheng Feng, newspaper, 1957 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - Liu Shurong file, 1968 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - Pang Xiusheng file, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Qiao Zhiwen materials, 1971 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Shi Ya materials, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Shen Xiuqin, Huo Jihuan, investigation report, 1977 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Huo Jihuan files, 1977 (Box-folder 11: 8)
- Can Kao Xiao Xi Magazine File, 1948-1987 (Box 12)
  - Can Kao Xiao Xi magazine copies, 1948 (Box-folder 12: 1-4)
  - "Rural Revolutionary Base History in the Second Civil War,", 1981 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - Inventory list, 1986 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - 55th anniversary edition, 1987 (Box-folder 12: 7)
- Pre and Post Cultural Revolution Materials, 1949-1988 (Box 13)
  - Civil Affairs Bureau work summary, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Three Antis Movement, punished party member registration form, 1952 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Trust company registration form, 1952 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Confidentiality regulations, 1954 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Supreme Court written judgements, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Counter-insurgency campaign, Han Yueshun files, 1955 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - Beijing Civil Affairs Bureau struggle, focus registration list, 1955 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Three Antis Movement, punished party member registration form, 1956 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Shatter the rightists' offensive, 1957 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Miscellaneous files from the Civil Affairs Bureau, 1959 (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - Diao Xiangfu file, 1962 (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - Five Antis Movement materials, 1964 (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - Unions roster, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 13)
  - High school forum, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 14)
  - Revolutionary critics, 1969 (Box-folder 13: 15)
  - Chinese Communist Party 9th National Representatives Conference, 1969 (Box-folder 13: 16)
  - Zhao Zhongxiu files, 1971 (Box-folder 13: 17)
  - Study materials, 1974 (Box-folder 13: 18)
  - Zhang Xiaoyou files, 1976 (Box-folder 13: 19)
  - Critics on the Gang of Four, 1977 (Box-folder 13: 20)
  - Xi Yu, spiritual civilization report, 1988 (Box-folder 13: 21)
  - Xi Yu, legal education survey report, 1988 (Box-folder 13: 22)
- Government Publications, 1919-2006 (Box 14-28)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes books, pamphlets, and brochures.
  - Beijing, Chongwen area, meeting materials, 1949-2004 (Box 14)
  - Beijing, Changping area, economic statistics, 1949-1978 (Box 14)
  - "National forest statistics,", 1973-1976 (Box 14)
  - National economic statistics, 1981 (Box 14)
  - "A History of Transportation and Industry,", 1983 (Box 14)
  - Discipline review files, 1986,1991-1994 (Box 14)
  - Rao He, economic statistics files, 2000-2001 (Box 14)
  - Counter-insurgency campaign, policy restriction files, 1956 (Box 15)
  - Wang Fenggang system, 1954 (Box 15)
  - Forestry statistics, 1987 (Box 15)
  - Rural economy file, 1949-1990 (Box 15)
  - Xiong Shi Chu Guan, A New Fourth Army Memoir, 1996 (Box 15)
  - Beijing, Xuanwu area, meeting materials, 1949-1994 (Box 15)
  - Wages files, 1973 (Box 15)
  - Bao Qing area, economic statistics, 1999-2000 (Box 15)
  - Justice workbook, 1978 (Box 15)
  - History of the Beijing Da Hua Radio Instrument Factory, 1958-1998 (Box 15)
  - Counter-insurgency, campaign materials, 1960 (Box 16)
  - Chang Zi county, economic statistics, 1973 (Box 16)
  - Beijing, Changping county, economic statistics, 1991 (Box 16)
  - Chinese Communist Party, national program policy file, 1991 (Box 16)
  - Yutai Harbor, Fujian province, name list, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Counter-insurgency struggle, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Establishment of the Regime, 1984 (Box 17)
  - Mass Production Movement, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Found a Party, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Wuhan, industrial and transportation history materials, 1982, 1984 (Box 17)
  - National economic plan statistics, 1956 (Box 17)
  - National forestry statistics, 1977-1981 (Box 17)
  - Urban work file, 1987 (Box 17)
  - Beijing, Chongwen area, police history material, 2002 (Box 17)
  - Fujian province, statistics materials, 1958 (Box 18)
  - Counter-revolutionary material in the counter-insurgency movement, 1956 (Box 18)
  - National economic statistics, 1949-1972 (Box 18)
  - Tibet, Changdu area, Three Rivers agribusiness plan, 1997 (Box 18)
  - Chinese trade union overview, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Army-owned real estate consolidation materials, 1991 (Box 18)
  - Urban construction statistics annual report, 1988-1990 (Box 19)
  - Fengman Power Plant Worker's Movement History, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Chinese democratic revolution, labor movement memorabilia, 1919-1949 (Box 20)
  - Counter-insurgency campaign, reports by the Department of Cultural Affairs, 1958-1963 (Box 21)
  - Da Qing, political work meeting materials, 1977 (Box 22)
  - "Tianjing Railway History,", 1984 (Box 22)
  - Beijing, Changping county, fourth census report, 1990 (Box 22)
  - Taiwanese figures, 1996 (Box 22)
  - Central leaders, name list and profiles, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Central governors' speeches about culture and art after the 16th Congress, 2006 (Box 22)
  - Beijing, Chang Ping area, census report, 2000 (Box 23)
  - Beijing, third census materials, 1982 (Box 23)
  - History of the Korean War, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Wuhan Labor Movement History, 1919-1949 (Box 23)
  - Labor reform legislation, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Chinese population materials, 1984-1985 (Box 24)
  - Chinese Revolutionary War History, 1927-1951 (Box 24)
  - Beijing, family plan survey report, 1998 (Box 24)
  - National work statistics, 1989 (Box 24)
  - Jurisprudence and Progressive Thinkers' Works, 1975
    - Pre-Qin Dynasty, 1975 (Box 25)
    - Han and Three Empire Period, 1975 (Box 25)
    - Tang, Song, Yuan Dynasty, 1975 (Box 25)
    - Qing Dynasty, 1975 (Box 25)
    - Appendix, 1975 (Box 25)
  - Chinese Communist Party, Yangquan history, 2003 (Box 25)
  - Chinese Contemporary History, 1987 (Box 25)
  - "Puyang Farm History,", 1956-1985 (Box 26)
  - People's Liberation Army, political regulations, 1978 (Box 26)
  - Chinese population materials, 1983 (Box 26)
  - Beijing, Changping county, third census data file, 1984 (Box 26)
  - Beijing, Changping county, 1990 census materials, 1992 (Box 26)
  - Sixth census, conference thesis, 1994 (Box 26)
  - Jing Ji Cha daily historiography seminar thesis, 2005 (Box 26)
  - Chinese Communist Party, labor movement articles, 1921-1945 (Box 27)
  - Sino-Russian border treaty, 1973 (Box 28)
  - Jian Bao newspaper collection (Box 28)
  - Hebei, Weichang county, third census materials, 1982 (Box 28)
  - Inmates extension material, 1984-1985 (Box 28)
  - Beijing, construction materials industry and main economic indicator statistics, 1990 (Box 28)
- Chinese Communist Party Posters, Cartoons and Postcards, 1933-1950 (Box 29)
  - "Visit to Mao Zedong," East Shandong, 1945 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Anti-Japanese sabotage, 1945 (Box-folder 29: 2)
  - Ren Min Hua Bao, Yenan (4 copies), 1946 (Box-folder 29: 3)
  - Shan Dong Hua Bao Dong Bei Hua Bao, miscellaneous pictorial supplements, 1946 (Box-folder 29: 4)
  - Chinese communist public health propaganda, 1945 (Box-folder 29: 5)
  - Charging He Siyuan with collaboration, 1945 (Box-folder 29: 6)
  - Reproductions of Chinese communist oil paintings, 1945 (Box-folder 29: 7)
    Includes "Mao Zedong meets Zhu De in Chingkangshan" (3 copies) and "Liberation!" (2 copies).
  - Jiao Tong Hua Bao, colored cartoons attacking collaborator, East Shandong, 1945 (Box-folder 29: 8)
  - Jiao Tong Hua Bao, cartoons attacking Kuomintang, with map of Chi-lu-yu liberated area, 1945 (Box-folder 29: 9)
  - Chinese communist poster, 1950 (Box-folder 29: 10)
  - On farm production in Beijing, in spring, 1949 (Box-folder 29: 11)
  - Ren Hua Bao, Zheng Xian, Shanxi Province, 1946 (Box-folder 29: 12)
  - "Farm Family Joy" (2 copies), 1945 (Box-folder 29: 13)
  - Communist caricatures of the life of Chiang Kai-shek (photostats of seven samples), 1945 (Box-folder 29: 14)
  - Peoples' Republic of China flags, 1945 (Box-folder 29: 15)
  - Peoples' Republic of China coat of arms, 1945 (Box-folder 29: 16)
  - Chinese communist propaganda postcards (8 sets), 1952 (Box-folder 29: 17)
  - Depicting the heads of Zhou Enlai, Zhu De, and Mao Zedong, black and white, Yenan, 1946 (Box-folder 29: 18)
  - Chinese communist war cartoons and posters, 1944 (Box-folder 29: 19)
  - Anti-Nazi eighth route army, Shandong, 1944 (Box-folder 29: 20)
  - Colored woodblock prints, 1950 (Box-folder 29: 21)
  - "Communist Song," with translation, circa 1933 (Box-folder 29: 22)
  - "The Actual Strength of the Red Army,", undated (Box-folder 29: 23)
  - Chinese communist war pictures, 1944 (Box-folder 29: 24)
  - Chinese communist cartoons, comparing Kuomintang and communist war efforts, 1944 (Box-folder 29: 25)
  - Depicting the head of Mao Zedong, black and white, Beijing, 1949 (Box-folder 29: 26)
  - Attacking alleged nationalist and puppet collaboration, undated (Box-folder 29: 27)
  - Woodblock prints (15 sheets), 1946 (Box-folder 29: 28)
  - "Celebrating the Sino-Soviet Treaty,", 1945 (Box-folder 29: 29)
  - "The Liberation of Chefoo," reproductions of snapshots of the civil war, undated (Box-folder 29: 30)
  - "Da Zhong Ri Bao, Beijing: Announcing the Communist Crossing of the Yangtze" and "Tianjin Ri Bao: Announcing the Communist Capture of Hangchow," special issue posters, 1949 (Box-folder 29: 31)
  - Shandong Hua Bao, 1945 (Box-folder 29: 32)
  - Chinese Trotskyist document, undated (Box-folder 29: 33)
- Compilations of Decisions Made Within the Party File, 1957-1969 (Box 30-31)
  - Anti-rightist movement material, 1957 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Party expel decisions, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 30: 2-4)
  - Rightist expel decisions, 1958 (Box-folder 30: 5-7)
  - Central leaders speeches, 1965 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Central party notification, 1967 (Box-folder 31: 2)
  - Great public critics special issue, 1967 (Box-folder 31: 3)
  - Red Guards, newspapers, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - Beijing Petroleum Institute, anti-rightist movement materials, 1957 (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - Rightists remarks, 1957 (Box-folder 31: 6)
  - Refuting Lin Xiling's fallacy, 1957 (Box-folder 31: 7)
  - Du Cao Hui Ji, anti-rightist material, 1957 (Box-folder 31: 8)
  - Mao Zedong correspondence manuscript, 1983 (Box-folder 31: 9)
- Red Guards Tabloids, 1967-1971 (Box 32-33)
  - Mao Zedong Thought Propaganda, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Red Workers, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Labor Critics, 1968 (Box 32)
  - Dong Feng Horn, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Tao Critics Paper, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Guang Dong Art and Cultural Paper, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Zhong Shan University Red Flag, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Oriental Red Paper, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Capital Red Guards, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Sports Newspaper, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Red Rebels, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Wu Han Steel Guang Zhou, newspaper, 1968 (Box 32)
  - New Peking University, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Jinggang Mountain, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Xian Feng, newspaper, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Workers' Revolt, newspaper (170 copies), 1967-1971 (Box 32-33)
- Communist Party Leaders Anthologies of Remarks File, 1950-1980 (Box 34)
  - "Political Learning Materials,", 1950 (Box 34)
  - "Chinese Democratic Revolution References,", 1951 (Box 34)
  - "Counter-revolutionary Groups,", 1955 (Box 34)
  - "Hai Rui's Resignation,", 1965 (Box 34)
  - "Be Vigilant and Splinter Right-Wing Conspiracy,", 1957 (Box 34)
  - "Concession Policy Issues,", 1965 (Box 34)
  - "Evaluation on Historical Figures,", 1966 (Box 34)
  - "Class Issues and Historicism,", 1966 (Box 34)
  - "Honest and Upright Official,", 1966 (Box 34)
  - Historical research and methodological issues, 1966 (Box 34)
  - Lin Biao and Jiang Qing, speech collection, 1966 (Box 34)
  - Comrade Lin Biao speech, 1967 (Box 34)
  - Zhou Yang, counter-revolutionary revisionist remarks, 1967 (Box 34)
  - Deng Xiaoping, reactionary remarks, 1967 (Box 34)
  - Liu Shaoqi, evidence of guilt, 1968 (Box 34)
  - Jiang Qing and Lin Biao, trial of counter-revolutionary clique record, 1980 (Box 34)
- Incremental Materials (Box 35)
  Additional materials not yet described.